<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[VU LAI]]></title><description><![CDATA[VU LAI]]></description><link>https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 14:30:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[About Me]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hi, I’m Vu Lai About me Facts: Gen Z. Aries. Speak Vietnamese (Mother tongue), English (Second language), and Chinese (Conversational…]]></description><link>https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/about/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/about/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Hi, I’m Vu Lai&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facts: Gen Z. Aries. Speak Vietnamese (Mother tongue), English (Second language), and Chinese (Conversational language)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used to work in sale (B2B &amp;#x26; B&amp;#x26;C) for 2 years and change my career path to product management (will be 2 years till the end of 2021). I will pursue Master degree in Information Systems at The University of Sheffield in September 2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work is my favorite topic including sharing work experience (especially moving from non-tech to tech), dealing with salary and benefits, learning from start-up, correcting sitting positions during work, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Besides work, I’m also keen on FIRE (Financial Independence, Retire Early) with some sub-topics related to different types of investment, passive income streams, and many more. But honestly, I’m an amateur and want to learn from you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m a fan of podcasts and Youtube and plan to do in the future (podcast first, Youtube later). Looking for co-hosts and partners &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m not a fan of subscription (I don’t subscribe Netfilx, Spotfiy or any service with subscription), although I have been working for 2 SaaS platforms, even managing the subscription process &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Besides a product management role, I also want to become a part-time lecturer at universities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About this blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The main objectives of this are to document and share the progress of connecting the dots in my career path, from non-tech to tech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other objectives are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to develop a “creating interest”, an interest of creating meaningful things, rather than pursue other “absorbing interests”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to document new knowledge and skills I learnt in product management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to improve English writing skill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At first, the content is mostly about lessons and experiences at my workplace. Later on, there will be other sub-topics in point 3 and interviews with experts and professionals working in other industries such as marketing, data science, human resource, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[No title]]></title><description><![CDATA[Vu Lai There’s always light even at night. What we need is broader sight.]]></description><link>https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Vu Lai&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s always light even at night. What we need is broader sight.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Contact Me]]></title><description><![CDATA[Get in Touch. If you’ve got an inquiry for a job or project,drop me a line at hello@hello.com or fill the form right here.]]></description><link>https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/contact/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/contact/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Get in Touch.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got an inquiry for a job or project,drop me a line at hello@hello.com or fill the form right here.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[10 myths about Product Requirements Document (PRD) - P1]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello! 
For whom is planning to or just broke into product management recently may find writing PRD so cool. Well, it is, until you have a…]]></description><link>https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/blog/10-myths-about-product-requirements-document-p1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/blog/10-myths-about-product-requirements-document-p1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello!
For whom is planning to or just broke into product management recently may find writing PRD so cool. Well, it is, until you have a chance to write it for complex features :) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily ask Google what PRD is and how to write it so I won’t repeat it because she (on my phone) is much smarter than me. However, I still embed some useful links that I’ve read at the end of this blog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, this blog aims to debunk myths about PRD for beginners based on my experiences. Hope it helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start the nightmare. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 630px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/503adc6ea8129b6e3b4981dbf59b1484/df51d/blog2.1-banner.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 100%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAUABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAABAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIDBAH/xAAVAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAAB1QpsOIIzaCykH//EABoQAQACAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAAgMREiH/2gAIAQEAAQUCjonjKt2IstR6xZLbbs7Z/8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIP/aAAgBAwEBPwEf/8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIP/aAAgBAgEBPwEf/8QAFxABAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAhMf/aAAgBAQAGPwJwqH//xAAaEAEAAwEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhMWFx/9oACAEBAAE/ITGkjTnybO1NCKbTOxaQBCAvsXmVPWf/2gAMAwEAAgADAAAAEOAXvf/EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACAh/9oACAEDAQE/EIP/xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABIP/aAAgBAgEBPxBj/8QAGhABAQEBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFBwf/aAAgBAQABPxAHJVh+ZtU3nHuiDQZLjGwp9TlOYb1R1xv3NKD4smNgSBuebCXwz8Wb/9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;blog2.1-banner&quot;
        title=&quot;blog2.1-banner&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/503adc6ea8129b6e3b4981dbf59b1484/828fb/blog2.1-banner.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/503adc6ea8129b6e3b4981dbf59b1484/ff44c/blog2.1-banner.jpg 158w,
/static/503adc6ea8129b6e3b4981dbf59b1484/a6688/blog2.1-banner.jpg 315w,
/static/503adc6ea8129b6e3b4981dbf59b1484/828fb/blog2.1-banner.jpg 630w,
/static/503adc6ea8129b6e3b4981dbf59b1484/0ede0/blog2.1-banner.jpg 945w,
/static/503adc6ea8129b6e3b4981dbf59b1484/3ac88/blog2.1-banner.jpg 1260w,
/static/503adc6ea8129b6e3b4981dbf59b1484/df51d/blog2.1-banner.jpg 2400w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Myth 1: The most important parts of a PRD are functional requirements and mock-ups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a high chance that stakeholders may become strangers who unexpectedly cancel all agreements on the release date when the deliverable is not working as their expectation. One of the most common problems causing the issue is that problem statement and goal sections in a PRD are not well defined. People are likely to take this section for granted, which turns out to be a surprisingly high possibility of wrong direction and unexpected increments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing previous PRDs, I’d say the two sections are the most crucial parts because they act as a compass for the whole document. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is mutually agreed that a new feature is not always the sole approach to tackle problems. There may be some alternatives such as improved process and workarounds which already exists or takes much less effort to implement. If the sections are documented carefully, a more fruitful and efficient approach may be selected, saving the company’s resources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My small tip is to avoid jumping into fancy things when the cores are not strongly persuasive. Always keep our mind open with no fixed solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Myth 2: “All I need to include in a PRD is information that is collected from stakeholders.”, PO said&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product life is not that easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;collected&lt;/code&gt; used in the sentence is incorrect because PO/PM is not the one who receives one-way requirements (We’re not secretaries) but try to put ourselves into stakeholder’s shoes and think of thousands of invisible scenarios. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Elicit&lt;/code&gt; is the correct terminology. Besides asking for more details in their response, expected behaviors in edges cases, many of which have never crossed their mind, must be elicited as much as possible, avoiding any surprises after release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, stakeholders say they want signup and login pages for a mobile app ASAP (As always).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were in this case, I would book a kick-off meeting to ask questions as following (Given that reasons for implementation are clear): &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are your expected signup/ login methods? Among them, which is must-have/ should-have/ could-have (MoSCoW method)?
… (then a few questions to understand their expectation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edge case 1: Given that users fail to log in 5 times, when they click Forgot password button and their registered email couldn’t be accessed to verify their identity, how should users solve the problem? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edge case 2: What do you think about the case that users can log in simultaneously with different credentials on different browsers? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, avoid asking obvious questions or raising unrealistic scenarios as it will be counter-productive. A tip here is that you can validate your assumptions by using a template “Please correct me if I’m wrong. In the case abc, the expected behavior is xyz.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Myth 3: Include everything, even obvious things, in a PRD even when the development team and PO/PM have worked with each other for a long time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insanely true. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the Scrum team has passed forming/storming/norming stages, it doesn’t mean that the PRD can be done without care. It is the backbone of the ideation phase, so not a single detail should be skipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circling back to the example, simple acceptance criteria that are not well defined to username is a prime example, where there is an expected constraint of valid email address; however, it is intentionally skipped because of the assumption that developers will apply the same practice from previous projects. In fact, they implement to accept all string. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That really shows how close PO/PM and the development team are :) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/R2m2NzVxQ3pbG/giphy.gif?cid=ecf05e47j0wrnip7ca8h31m8c3h2ri1k45sk3726lrfqn7w6&amp;#x26;rid=giphy.gif&amp;#x26;ct=g&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Myth 4: Always dive to mock-ups before going to PRD details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It depends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my perspective, if stakeholders confidently answer challenging questions in detail and know some unknowns during elicitation, it’s a clear signal that they somewhat understand their needs. Hence, mock-ups linked in a user flow will be helpful in the ideation phase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the happy case seldom occurs, especially with complicated features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirement elicitation may take many rounds due to various unknowns that need to be validated with other dependencies. During this time, it’s not surprising that a 180-degree change may happen, leading to demand for updates in mock-ups accordingly. Not sure how much mock-ups’ value adds to the document’s clarity, but in my opinion, there’s no use updating mock-ups with a high level of volatility in requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I often draw flowcharts in validation meetings and update them along the way as it’s not only powerful in illustration but also convenient in maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Myth 5: What stakeholders request must be delivered without negotiation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although features/ enhancements are made for end-users, it’s not mandatory to strictly implement all of their expected functionalities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Narrowing the scope down and dividing it into smaller phases are two common choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the first option, PM/PO can negotiate with stakeholders to utilize current product’s capabilities (at least in a short-term period) for requests which have alternatives, especially when resource is limited. Or, if there is any requirement that is not really valid, don’t hesitate to push back. We have that power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if all requests are non-negotiable? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time to make use of planning skills to have deliverables in some phases. Technical view is essential here to be able to have usable increments in every phase with no dependency. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apply Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) to build a romantic relationship]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello!
Some share that it’s a bit hard to remember all steps of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), so in this blog, I want to share one…]]></description><link>https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/blog/apply-software-development-life-cycle-to-build-a-romantic-relationship/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbyglass.netlify.app/blog/apply-software-development-life-cycle-to-build-a-romantic-relationship/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello!
Some share that it’s a bit hard to remember all steps of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), so in this blog, I want to share one practical use case of SDLC in real life, romantic relationship, to memorize it easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 630px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/a0d58461d8db677c22fed732cafa73bf/23296/blog1-banner.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 66.45569620253164%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAANCAYAAACpUE5eAAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAACLklEQVQ4y31T225SQRQdwJbScmmrqDEaUxujiWm9tF5q01YfjKXYC8ZbNaZ/oP6BfcHbk5d+RX0isWJpwuEkxOIhBEsI8AcQEoTwQLgvzx4yJ4fauJOVPXNmzzpr1p5hDrsVdtsAKFsHLLBZ+yG+0VisiSxA86FBO8+MMczNziASiYDpN5w6eQJHnYf5fNBhw/FjTp71ZGI8POTAIRPj62/feNFqtUDBRKFB/cvUjetYffIYbrcLS4v38OjhA5wZOc1JiIA2kypSTqpu35pDPB6HiEaj0VFIhdeuTuK+ZwXPnq7CveCCx7PMx6OjI3yzUUWfuUdVZeD1H96/6yJqt9sdhYLw/LmzmJy4zDFx5RLGxy5g+uYUt2Ft7TnW11/j4vgYZmemkUgkNLJms8kzERKY8MXS14veHhOHWUW/xcyVvXr5ArVaDb/39lAoFFCtVv9RJbKmUPhISgWcR4a5r183N6FEo/B6vZoa+gE1QUBPzPZfBSKjBpiMnQ5ubX3jxZVKRSM8KASxdmTRSbqLdNT5u3eQSqW0YhHU1e3tH4jFYkgmk7xGv870qowGxo/6+dPHLtOF4RSyLEOSggiHw5CCQUSjCnK5HPL5PK9lelULrnmk02nNj/0dpAhJEnZ3f0IOheD3+xFSsyyHEAgEUK/Xwch4eh0bG18OvFeCTMwVRYHP58Mv9Znt7ARU0u+cSDvyyvISMpnMf1Xpx6VSSUUR5XIZ2WwWxeKfLlv+AoqVoXTgvxopAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;blog1-banner&quot;
        title=&quot;blog1-banner&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/a0d58461d8db677c22fed732cafa73bf/f058b/blog1-banner.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/a0d58461d8db677c22fed732cafa73bf/c26ae/blog1-banner.png 158w,
/static/a0d58461d8db677c22fed732cafa73bf/6bdcf/blog1-banner.png 315w,
/static/a0d58461d8db677c22fed732cafa73bf/f058b/blog1-banner.png 630w,
/static/a0d58461d8db677c22fed732cafa73bf/23296/blog1-banner.png 675w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SDLC in brief&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before jumping to interesting parts, let’s revise SDLC quickly with some of my add-ons (Freely skip this section if you get bored with theories)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;No.&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Step&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stakeholder analysis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This is not usually defined in SDLC, but for me, it’s essential to note down all involved stakeholders, their influences, and interest. They are our judges anw&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Requirement elicitation &amp;#x26; analysis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Besides detailed requirements, problem statement/ business need, goal(s), project scope, and success metric(s) should be covered.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Research/ Feasibility study&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;For complex projects/systems with many uncertainties, conducting market research or preparing a Proof of Concept before the design phase saves my life.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Based on requirements and discovery, high-level and low-level design (may not need both) will be defined, coupled with the project team. A detailed analysis with acceptance criteria [1] and mockups should be on the table at the end of this stage.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Development&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The name says it all. Developers code non-stop.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Based on acceptance criteria and expected behaviors of specific scenarios, QAs test the system’s functionality in testing environments. Devs will be called many times if bugs are not entirely extinct.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deployment &amp;#x26; Launch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Training before a roll-out is necessary if you don’t want your phone to become a hotline. Also applied for alignment before deployment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Measurement &amp;#x26; Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Control laziness to measure the efficiency of the system/ feature based on success metrics and prevent it from a swarm of bugs.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More definitions can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techopedia.com/definition/22193/software-development-life-cycle-sdlc&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apply SDLC to relationship management?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s imagine that you are a man who wants to follow a woman after seeing her Facebook. Given that she is still single to be easy (lucky you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 0: Stakeholder analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just some examples of stakeholders are picked. Others, such as her children (hopefully not), are ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Priority&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Stakeholders&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Interest&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Influence&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Action (RACI matrix)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Her&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Project sponsor + customer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Hopefully high&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;You&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Project sponsor + team + customer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Extremely high&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;R,A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Her family members&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Consultants&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Medium&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Her married friends&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Subject matter experts&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Medium&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Your best friend&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Project team (mainly beer partner)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Extremely low&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides listing all possible stakeholders, don’t forget to get their interest and influence, by all means, to &lt;strong&gt;prioritize&lt;/strong&gt; and have a clear &lt;strong&gt;plan&lt;/strong&gt; to satisfy each of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you can approach her friends who frequently like and comment on her posts, have pictures with children on their personal accounts, and ask for her favorite dishes and drinks. This will “satisfy” her friends now and her later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 1: Requirement elicitation &amp;#x26; analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time to chat with her and other stakeholders. Besides self-introduction and casual conversation, wisely ask for her current status and thoughts about relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, she has been alone for a while and wants to find someone to share. Hence, her &lt;strong&gt;“business” need&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;goal&lt;/strong&gt; are the same as yours, which is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After talking with her friends, you realize that she wants a partner, not a husband for now, meaning that the project scope is smaller; however, if you have skills and capacity, you can help her realize other needs, a life-long husband, and expand the scope. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the goal and scope of having a partner, &lt;strong&gt;objectives&lt;/strong&gt; namely becoming her close friend in 2 months, her top-of-mind friend at lunch should be clearly defined. Some of which can be based on to form success metrics [2], i.e., how many days in a week she actively texts you to share something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/521WnOwm4pKjPJ2G7r/giphy.gif?cid=ecf05e47g22y85xsgd3xxqlry19us3f3r2z07so3o3rkt1ml&amp;#x26;rid=giphy.gif&amp;#x26;ct=g&quot; alt=&quot;gif1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t forget to note down the &lt;strong&gt;estimated budget&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;release date&lt;/strong&gt; of this life-changing project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 2: Research/ Feasibility study&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When flirting, try to &lt;strong&gt;research&lt;/strong&gt; more information about her to make sure that you are somewhat “qualified” in her eyes. Some types of feasibilities [3]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g., With your monthly salary, can you afford a Hermes clutch on her birthday as it’s her favorite branded item?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g., Is she over 18? 🙅&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g., Are you a lady killer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g., Is it possible to get her official agreement after 6 months, regarding the current situation of both?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more research you conduct, the more resources you can save later. Highly recommend using &lt;strong&gt;Proof of Concept (PoC)&lt;/strong&gt; template for long-term usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proof of Concept is a model created to validate the design of a system without modelling the appearance, materials used in the creation of work, or processes/workflows ultimately used by the stakeholders &lt;em&gt;(BABOK v3, A GUIDE TO THE BUSINESS ANALYSIS BODY OF KNOWLEDGE)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 3: Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you still believe that she is the one and you also fit her, congratulations! You’re so patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now formulate &lt;strong&gt;high-level to low-level strategies&lt;/strong&gt; to approach her. Make sure to include &lt;strong&gt;work breakdown structure&lt;/strong&gt; to avoid missing items as the following simple example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 630px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/9abcccd040dc4cbe617fb6732e32dd57/a2b88/blog1-becomeherpartner.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 48.734177215189874%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAKCAIAAAA7N+mxAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAABfklEQVQoz31RTU/CQBDl9xn/gzEm/gRP3j0Zr8aLBw9yMfFgtBpFEQOtpIAIFCilFIptaaH0c/u5OK0GlRBfZvcwO++9mdnMYh0wXshT9zLHZYmOIFlRhNeWZSCNf3EAsu4dXzR394nNnezG9vnW3tXRWY0VLXiK8R+VzIohKCE/UnVUrEmHp+WDE/KuJIwU2/WiNc6agcaaLarOzPKjGIcxhls1EIQ4dYaqDRmom9lBX7bGmoP8+IdcZWWC7BbqI0F1lvZ0R74udu7LvXxN0MwAslPTa/JqlVUU3bUcTzeR6fhJ2yjE75zMiRrG30OBGYSgmE3uo81LnYEC7XjhgmZGBbrbHsi8OBEVIyG7Ac7R/QeKydM9aeam7olGnZvcPNeJl0apPrBRGET4jVXIxlCdo68OU2cgV4a3JEuQ7CPN89I8SucEAmwEwvHi5UpjHANwioTshbhQ4Z6oRp5qPr4yhpMMuf5nV7YNJ4R+ekq5JdLMmGqJlhsuyfhflU8CLC4DcipIigAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Work breakdown structure / WBS (Example)&quot;
        title=&quot;Work breakdown structure / WBS (Example)&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/9abcccd040dc4cbe617fb6732e32dd57/f058b/blog1-becomeherpartner.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/9abcccd040dc4cbe617fb6732e32dd57/c26ae/blog1-becomeherpartner.png 158w,
/static/9abcccd040dc4cbe617fb6732e32dd57/6bdcf/blog1-becomeherpartner.png 315w,
/static/9abcccd040dc4cbe617fb6732e32dd57/f058b/blog1-becomeherpartner.png 630w,
/static/9abcccd040dc4cbe617fb6732e32dd57/a2b88/blog1-becomeherpartner.png 908w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Work breakdown structure / WBS (Example)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WBS is a hierarchical decomposition of the total scope of work to be carried out by the project team to accomplish the project objectives and create the required deliverables &lt;em&gt;(A Guide to the Project Management Body of Knowledge (PMBOK® Guide) – Fifth Edition PMI, 2013)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the diagram, you work closely with your beer partner to document &lt;strong&gt;detailed plans&lt;/strong&gt; with acceptance criteria and different scenarios that may happen, e.g., Be prepared if you bump into your ex when hanging out with her. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In IT projects, it’s necessary to &lt;strong&gt;get sign-off&lt;/strong&gt; from all stakeholders before development but in “romantic projects”, no one dares approve. Is that the reason why many experienced project managers/ product managers are still single?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 4: Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just implement your plan with the project team. Hope that not all of the plans fail. But if so, please go back to step 1 and 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 5: Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage, both of you are moving one step closer to the golden time. Now you can utilize the acceptance criteria to evaluate &lt;em&gt;how deep your love&lt;/em&gt; is before proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are usually 2 possible scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All criteria are fulfilled. Woohoo! Passing them almost guarantees your proposal plan. But man, don’t count your chickens before they hatch. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few criteria are not passed. No worries, try to revise what has been done and rework until meeting them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if her best friend shares that there has been a guy who looks like CR7 (not you) hanging out with her frequently in the past few weeks. It sounds an alarm bell about the failed objective – Become her top-of-mind friend, where you should send more messages, call her more, ship more snacks, etc., to win her back. Don’t be scared due to his fame … although it really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 6: Deployment &amp;#x26; Launch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You two have made a lot of progress, and it’s time you propose, and she will say 🆗.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hang on… It’s not that easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes she may nod her head when you are joking about the proposal (Testing environment), but when it truly happens (Production environment), she may say: “I’m sorry. You’re so good, but abcxyz …”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you &lt;strong&gt;form an alignment&lt;/strong&gt; with her family members, her friends in advance (Align with stakeholders before deployment), your chance of success will be much higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 7: Measurement &amp;#x26; Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After she says yes, it’s not done. Life is not that easy, man!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may know, the first few months are the easiest time to break up because you two don’t have enough time to understand and sympathize with each other. Hence, “&lt;strong&gt;measuring&lt;/strong&gt;” the health of your relationship periodically based on the defined success metrics above is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess you don’t want her to say something like this after the first week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/ukinterns.society19.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/breakup-gif.gif?resize=500%2C230&amp;#x26;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;gif2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, you may need to spend time taking care of her frequently (maintain the system), especially when you want to expand the scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t tell me that you believe in the fact that I’m a master of love 🤣. In fact, I’m still single.
Simply wanna write down some lessons that I’ve learned through some professional and “special” projects. Looking forward to your thoughts and comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Disclaimer: This blog is served as educational and entertaining material, and should not be considered as relationship advice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] International Institute of Business Analysis. (2015). Acceptance and Evaluation Criteria. In &lt;em&gt;A guide to the business analysis body of knowledge: BABOK.&lt;/em&gt; essay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Kloppenborg, T. J., Tesch, D., &amp;#x26; King, B. (2012). Twenty-first century project success measures: evolution, interpretation, direction. Paper presented at PMI® Research and Education Conference, Limerick, Munster, Ireland. Newtown Square, PA: Project Management Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;em&gt;SDLC: Phases &amp;#x26; Models of Software Development Life Cycle.&lt;/em&gt; (n.d.). Guru99. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guru99.com/software-development-life-cycle-tutorial.html&quot;&gt;https://www.guru99.com/software-development-life-cycle-tutorial.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>